<html>
    <entry id="approval_ts">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: Timestamp (**)
The time of the most recent approval.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="approved">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: Boolean (false)
(Archaic) if this is approved or not. This has been replaced with the
status property but is updated in tandem with it. Use status instead.

See also: status]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="approver">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
The name of the approver. Generally this ought to be something that does identify
the person or process doing the approval. In the case of humans, this can
be their email or something similar, like their EPPN. In the case of admin
clients, it should be the unique identifier for that client.

The aim of this is to allow for auditing and tracking in case there is
some question about how or why a client was approved, revoked, etc.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>

    <entry id="status">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: String ("none")
The status of this approval. The recognized values are

    none : No operations have been done on the approvals
  denied : The appoval is explicitly denied
approved : The approval is accepted
 revoked : The approval was accepted, then revoked.
 pending : The approval is still awaiting approval.

In the course of operation of OA4MP, if a status of "none" or "denied" is
found, attempts to use the client are rejected with a message that the client
is not approved. If a client attempts to register itself through the client management
endpoint, then it has a status of "pending". ]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="approve">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Command.
Approve the current record.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="client_id">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (**)
This is the identifier of the client associated with this approval record.
When a client is created, an approval record should be created with a
status of "none". ]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="about">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[This store manages the approval for all clients. The approvals
are separate to allow more flexibility. All clients -- regular, admin, ersatz
have their approvals stored here.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
</html>
<!--
   approval_ts  approved  approver  client_id*  description  status

approve          show



-->
    <!--
 entry templates, without and with examples. These are not indented since
 we need to control whitespace and our ever so helpful editor adds it when
 any is detected, leading to bad output.

<entry id="">
<body>
<![CDATA[]]>
</body>
</entry>

<entry id="">
<body>
<![CDATA[]]>
</body>
<example>
<![CDATA[]]>
</example>
</entry>
          -->