<html>
    <entry id="access_token">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (--) 
The current access token. Note that this means the OA4MP unique identifier.
The configuration may specify that a JWT is returned, but that is not this.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="access_token_valid">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Boolean (false) 
If the current access token is valid. This may be set false using the
revocation endpoint, for instance.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="auth_grant">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (--) 
The authorization grant issued at the start of the flow. This is usually
the same as the temp_token.

See also: temp_token]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="auth_time">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Timestamp (**) 
The authorization time for this transaction. This may not be the same as the
time the transaction was created if, e.g., there is a device flow and the user takes some time
to authorize it. It does, however, give an fixed point for when the transaction starts to be used.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="authz_grant_lifetime">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Integer (-1) 
The lifetime in milliseconds that the authorization grant is valid.
N.B. That this is used in garbage collection if there is no access token. In that case,
an expired authorization grant and missing access token means that the flow has been abandoned,
since no access token will be issued after this lifetime.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="callback_uri">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--) 
Not a list! As per the OAuth spec., the authorization code flow is started
with a valid callback uri (meaning, it matches, as a string exactly one of the callbacks that
the client has registered), and subsequent call to the token endpoint must contain exactly the
same callback or the request is rejected. This attribute records the callback, if applicable,
the user started the flow with. Note that there is not callback specified in the
device flow.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="certificate">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--) 
The PEM encoded X509 certificate, if any, for this user. If the user was permitted
to get a certificate and got one through the getCert endpoint, then it would be cached here,
so subsequent calls to the getCert endpoint would return the same certificate.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="certlifetime">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Integer (0) 
The lifetime of the cert as requested by the lifetime parameter in the initial request.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="certreq">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--) 
The PEM encoded X509 certificate request.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="client_id">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (--) 
The identifier of the client making this request. This will be set by the system and managed
by it eventually, but initially it is not set.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="expires_in">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Integer (0) 
The lifetime *of the access token* in milliseconds. This was named long ago
in OAuth 1 when there were not refresh tokens or other such things and the expiration of the
access token was synonomous with the lifetime of the entire flow.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="is_rfc_8628">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Boolean (false) 
Internal flag if this transaction is part of a device flow. This has no
reason to ever be altered and exists as a separate flag in the store so outstanding device flows
may be searched for and evaluted at garbage collection, e.g.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="myproxyUsername">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--) 
For X509 certificates, there is a trust relationship with the MyProxy servers
that issue certificates. They may require this and it may be set by the system to fulfill any
contract.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="nonce">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--) 
If the client sends a nonce in the initial (authorization code) flow, we stash
it here, since as per the spec we return it at times. OA4MP does not care about it and does nothing
but hand it back at the required times so the client can use it for its own internal bookkeeping. ]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="proxy_id">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (--) 
The identifier of the proxy used in authorization. This is needed (and managed by
the system) in the course of constructing callbacks to the proxy server.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="refresh_token">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (--) 
The unqiue identifier for the refresh token.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="refresh_token_lifetime">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Integer (0) 
The lifetime of the refresh token in milliseconds.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="refresh_token_valid">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Boolean (false) 
If this refresh token is valid. It may be set to false in the revocation endpoint.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="req_state">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--) 
Clients may include a state parameter in their request. This is stored here and
returned as needed. For instance, all standard OAuth errors (to the callback endpoint)
require that the state parameter be included.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="scopes">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: List of strings. ([]) 
The complete set of scopes in the original request.

See also: validated_scopes]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="states">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: JSON (--) A very complex object with "no user serviceable parts". This may include
the following:
       comment : a comment from the system to help make sense of this
   proxy_state : The state object for the proxy. This includes all of the access and refresh tokens,
                 for instance, that are necesarry to manage the proxy. This may be quite large.
                 It will also, for instance, include its own set of claims asserted by the proxy.
        claims : the claims that are asserted in the id token.
    flow_state : the flow state, i.e., a state object that tells the system how the flow should
                 be managed. This can be set in scripts (where it is a stem) to do things like
                 deny all access from that point forward.
claims_sources : A list of serialized state objects for claim sources.
  script_state : The serialized state of the QDL interpreter. This is stashed between execution
                 phases. This is what allows you to, e.g., set a variable in the pre_auth phases
                 and have it seamlessly available in the post_token phase.
                 It may be viewed with the show_qdl_state command and may be set with the set_qdl_state
                 commmand, but that is triage, properly.

See also: show_qdl_state, set_qdl_state, claims, tokens
    ]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="temp_token">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (**)
This is the unique identifier for this transaction. It is the same as the authorization grant,
and the name of the field comes from OAuth 1 and remains for historical reasons.

See also: temp_token_valid ]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="temp_token_valid">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Boolean (false)
Flag for vailidity of the authorization grant.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="usercode">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
Device Flow.
This is the usercode generated in the device flow. It exists as a separate property so that is
may be searched on more easily.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="username">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
The name that the user used in their log on.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="validated_scopes">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: List of strings (--)
If the client has strict_scopes set to false, then this is the intersection of those and the
scopes that are stored in the scopes property. ]]>
   <example>
   <![CDATA[E.g.
In the initial request the user sends
openid profile email read:/frames write:segDB

and the scopes property contains
openid profile email org.cilogon.userinfo

Then this property contains
openig profile email

This is used later to determine which mutable scopes are requested.]]>
   </example>
       </body>
    </entry>

    <entry id="verifier_token">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (--)
Deprecated!
This was used in OAuth 1. ]]>
       </body>
    </entry>

    <entry id="show_qdl_state">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Command. 
This will show the serialized QDL state for this transaction. ]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="set_qdl_state">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Command. 
Set the QDL state for this transaction. This is a very low-level command
that allows you to change the stored state. Mostly this is used in emergencies, such as a bad
script has written some nonsense to the state which is preventing the flow from working.

See also: show_qdl_state]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="claims">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Command. 
Show the current claims for this transaction. This looks it up in the state and prints it.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="tokens">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Command. 
Print the current tokens for this transaction. See the --help for this command.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>

    <entry id="GC">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Garbage Collection. Transactions are automatically deleted once they are not
longer used. The logic for this may be quite complex, since a transaction may have a variety
of tokens that are associated with it. There are tools for running GC and querying it.

See also: gc_check, gc_run. gc_lock]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="get_by_at">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Command.
Get a transaction using its access token.]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="about">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Transactions are the major workhorse for OA4MP. These are largely managed
by the system and do not really require anything. The tools are supplied, however, in
cases where there is an issue that needs to be addressed, so there is access to the complete
state of any flow. Note that exchange records refer to transactions, so there are tools supplied
here that allows you to do looks ups there too.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="gc_check">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Command.
Checks if the current transaction can be garbage collected]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="gc_lock">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[Command.
Set, query or remove locks from the transaction table or from the token table.

A lock is a special object with a reserved id, usually gc:lock. When garbage collection
starts, this is written to the table and remains until the garbage collection has finished,
at which point the lock is removed. The reason for this is that in cases where there are multiple
instances of OA4MP accessing the same store (e.g. a load balancer) or that there is an enormous
number of transactions (hence so slow that GC has not ended before the thread to start the next
round of clean up begins), this ensures that there will be no race conditions or other errors.

It is possible though that there may be instances where the JVM exits unexpectedly in which case
the lock will remain, preventing garbage collection. This command will let you check if there is
such a lock and remove it. ]]>
       </body>
    </entry>
</html>
<entry id="gc_run">
   <body>
<![CDATA[Command.
Run garbage collection manually on the store. This may be advisable in certain edge cases,
such as recovering from some calamity, but generally this should be treated as a triage tool,
not a standard one.]]>
   </body>
</entry>
    <!--  List of attributes
       access_token            callback_uri            description             proxy_id                scopes                  user_code
       access_token_valid      certificate             expires_in              refresh_token           states                  username
       auth_grant              certlifetime            is_rfc_8628             refresh_token_lifetime  temp_token              validated_scopes
       auth_time               certreq                 myproxyUsername         refresh_token_valid     temp_token*             verifier_token
       authz_grant_lifetime    client_id               nonce                   req_state               temp_token_valid

       list of commands
encode
gc_check   tokens
gc_lock    set_qdl_state
gc_run
get_by_at  show_qdl_state
    -->
    <!--
        entry template
    <entry id="">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[]]>
       </body>
    </entry>

    -->
    <!--
    <entry id="">
       <body>
  <![CDATA[]]>
       </body>
       <example>
   <![CDATA[
   ]]>
        </example>
    </entry>
          -->

