<html>
    <entry id="at_issuer">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
The issuer that will be put in every access token in the VO unless locally
overridden.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="created">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: Integer (**)
The time in ms. at which this VO was created.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="default_key_id">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
The id of the JSON Web Key that will be used for signing. ]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="discovery_path">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
Used in the discovery endpoint for constructing and resolving the
well-known page. This is *not* a complete path, but is of the form

host/vi

So for instance, if your site is at

https://login.bgsu.edu/oauth2

and you have a discover_path of

login.bgsu.edu/my_issuer

then the resulting discovery page would be generated at

https://login.bgsu.edu/oauth2/.well-known/openid-configuration/my_issuer

and the server would respond to requests for

https://login.bgsu.edu/.well-known/openid-configuration/my_issuer

by returning the generated page. Of course, various entries in it would have
their paths constructed from this as well, such
as the jwks_uri (which is where all the custom signing keys for this VO might
reside at

https://login.bgsu.org:8443/oauth2/certs/my_issuer

in some cases depending upon other configuration in the server, this may vary a bit with
the addition of port numbers.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="issuer">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
The default issuer for every client in this VO, unless locally overridden.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="json_web_keys">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: JSON (--)
A set of keys as per RFC 7515 (https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc7517). These
can/should be auto generated for the VO.

See also: default_key_id]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="last_modified">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: Integer (**)
The timestamp in milliseconds that this VO was last saved.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="title">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: String (--)
A human-readable string. Generally this should make sense to whoever administers this VO.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="valid">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: Boolean (true)
Is this VO valid/enabled? Setting this flag to false -- a serious step -- immediately shuts down
use of this VO and any attempt by any client to start a flow will fail. Mostly this exists as a
drastic tool in case, e.g., the VO has somehow been compromised.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="vo_id">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Property: Identifier (**)
A standard unique identifier for this VO. Note that any admin client in the VO should use this
and set it to both the client's vo and vo_uri.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="print_keys">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Command.
Print a short report on the current set of JSON web keys for this VO, if any.]]>
    </body>
    <example>
        <![CDATA[ vi>print_keys /prod:fnal/vo_1
Found keys are:
  89F07558E2304FB6891C94A0E573C385: alg =RS384, use=sig
  79E85A32A61FF5E979A3FDEF30A0BCF4: alg =RS512, use=sig
  2978FF548A55A739502E3BC64A58E2B2: alg =RS256, use=sig

In this case, the ids, algorithm and use (sig means signature, which is the most common
use in OA4MP).]]>
    </example>
    </entry>
    <entry id="new_keys">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Command.
Creates a completely new set of keys for this VO.]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="about">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Virtual Organization.
OA4MP supports multiple issuers through its "virtual organization" mechanism.
A VO (virtual organization) has its own issuer, discovery endpoint and signing keys.

How's it work?
--------------
A VO exists outside of all clients. Admin clients may be added to the VO in which case all
of the VO environment (keys, issuers, etc.) is automatically inherited by any client.
It is possible to locally override this either in the client's cfg property or in a script.

How to make one?
----------------
Choose an id (that is a url) and use that. This identifier is only ever used internally,
so something like

production:/vo/caltech/igwn

is just fine. Then use this with the create command and select Y to edit the client. The
reason is that the logic flow for the client is followed. Read the prompts and do what
they say and you should have a fully functional VO at the end. You can test this by going to
your new well-known endpoint, which should be live at this point.

Uses
----
Any admin client is added to the VO by setting its vo_uri (and vo) property to be
the same as the vo_uri property here. Again, this is live and should be available for
testing immediately.
]]>
    </body>
    </entry>
    <entry id="test 1">
    <body>
    <![CDATA[Yo!]]>
    </body>
    </entry>

</html>
    <!--
oa2>use vo
  vi>list_keys
at_issuer  created  default_key_id  description  discovery_path  issuer  json_web_keys  last_modified  title  valid  vo_id*
  vo>/commands
                 print_keys
 new_keys

 entry templates, without and with examples. These are not indented since
 we need to control whitespace and our ever so helpful editor adds it when
 any is detected, leading to bad output.

<entry id="">
<body>
<![CDATA[]]>
</body>
</entry>

<entry id="">
<body>
<![CDATA[]]>
</body>
<example>
<![CDATA[]]>
</example>
</entry>
          -->